[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard
hello my very best to you and yours
junkie I love podcasts recommendation
before we get going today it's going to
be in the form of the TED talk I think
this one's around 18 minutes it is from
Paul Stamets sta M ETS and it's called
six ways that mushrooms can save the
world something like that definitely
worth checking out he also has a movie
that recently came out in theaters
fantastic fungi he has an episode two
episodes with Joe Rogan on that podcast
super fascinating to learn about that
sort of thing if you're locked in during
this current quarantine might be a good
time to just explore different things
that that that you want to learn not
your typical things step outside of your
zone maybe kind of distract your mind
with all this crazy news going on take
care of yourself let's get going to the
podcast we got Maddie Alice Wu no reason
Maddie Maddie Maddie Maddie welcome so
john caird love podcast how are you
today I'm stoked to be here I'm stuck
then you are Here I am I want to start
this out with what did you listen to on
the way here to be honest no I i real
ascend for the second or third time to
Nate ansmann first episode yeah you know
what you told me that before maybe I
just wanted you to repeat it so I'm like
yeah I just listened to it I did yeah we
were talking about just growth like it's
just so cool to see see someone grow
like you know you we have an image of
people especially in our small town we
have an image of of who someone is and
like who we know them to be or where
we've seen them in certain ways but but
as time progresses and we get older like
there's now this
allowing room for people to change and
breathe it's just so cool it is it's
inspiring yeah no I
music-wise what do you listen to music
wise yeah well we're being honest again
not anything that my grandmother would
like me to listen to but no I know I
listen to a lot of rap like like hard
rap
what would our thought if I know well on
Spotify rap caviar is my one of my go to
playlist just very here and there no but
um a lot of rap just to get me I did
think I don't I always need a little
boost so I feel like that's just it's
not who I am you know the songs mean
like I you know yeah you know I don't I
just like that that hardness we'll know
but if I'm not listening to rap no like
new country probably so there's a very
vast yeah um to be honest I was kind of
hoping that you would mention new
country because I'm always like you
gotta tell me who's hot right now I am
missing out on the country but okay who
do you like that within the last year is
there any like songs country why I said
I'm gonna be basic I'm gonna say Luke
Holmes Luke okay he and his lyrics I do
those lyrics do hit me and I can totally
relate with like his music is like super
relatable for me or like for my past or
my life so I really like him who else do
I like it country I don't know no I'm
more just like some I always have to
have something in the background so if
I'm not if I'm not you know if I'm just
here and there you know tootin around
town whatever yeah one of those if I'm
like on my way to something yeah
definitely rap but if I've got my
daughter was me we're definitely kids
Bob or some new country she's down with
to you but I never hit VeggieTales not a
thing dude
I remember I grew up listening to those
and like I was not I didn't I didn't
have a family that was like into them
into that side of me engine anything it
was just I thought it was so good
another song a classic they had songs
about like hair brushes and this guy who
travels around and he does I mean no
it's educational he's our age very
annoying very like bright orange bright
blue outfit he's very out there but
great for kids the kids love them yeah
so it's worse than Steve on Blue's Clues
I'll give you that Steve from Blue's
Blue's do too so I watch this thing a
couple years ago you might have seen
this it was like a it was like a Steve's
life after being Steve or something like
that or wait was Steve the first
character because I know they replaced
him Steve and Joe I'm so embarrassed
I don't know but I watched this thing
where it like it was a video interview
with him like later on he's like forty
involved and he's just like I'm just a
normal guy and it's kind of funny cuz
your dream had he missed the clue but
her brain is like no no you're you're
Steve yeah where's blue he's not here I
don't understand
that's so um so you're um your mother
what's my teacher and I think it was
there great right we should have been
there my stepmom yeah same oh no she's
still teaching she remembers you we
talked about you know this is anything
good no all good thing no I think she
knows well let me see your sister too no
yeah yeah I mean we just you came up in
conversation up when we were talking
about no you know scheduled this podcast
whatever no I don't I didn't really tell
anybody cuz I wanted to be you know like
it cool you know I did talk to her about
it and yeah she's super excited yeah is
it so bringing up cuz it's just growing
up again I'm just growing off they're
like growing older to be differently
we're talking about me it's so weird how
life works like I would have never
thought that like make look we're having
this great conversation like we're here
but like the connection of like
I was however many years old you know um
growing up in a small town our town is
our town is cool what's okay
yeah I always hated that I always hated
the like when people like overdo the
joke about drugs and stuff it's like
yeah what's your what's your view of
have you lived here whole life okay all
Cowlitz County it's still like it's
still oh yeah yeah I've been here too I
have grown I used to be like I didn't
like it I was like my I'm too cool for
my town like yeah I'm here I don't know
that was all about but now I just I love
it and like I'm it we're a small town
here now you know I totally I love this
- what's your what's your view on our
town like like if you had to describe it
to someone who's like oh that looks like
a pretty town and you're like I'm gonna
sell this town the lake the lake is
gorgeous oh my god it is right we know
we have met you know anywhere I feel
like anywhere you go know you know
there's gonna be homeless
there's gonna be drugs there's gonna be
no no crime well whatever no yeah I
think that you know you get that
anywhere so um yeah yeah yeah meet up
for me now I got my parents were born
and raised in Long Bay Oh No and they
add me and yeah you know a lot of people
don't know I know a lot of people
through them you know to me I've lived
here forever and no I don't know there's
just so much no I don't I don't know
like why do I choose Longview I don't
know like you know I don't know to be
honest like it's not bad like for me
what I like I like to be outside and
there's plenty of things no no they were
close to everything you know I don't
know if I want city I've got Seattle
I've got Portland right you know we're
close to that if I want like mountains
know where within you know you know what
I mean we got were close to that too so
like yeah I have everything within you
know a short drive to so but long yeah I
don't know I'm not specifically stuck
too long
right but I do think that I don't know
yeah I think long be like when we would
consider our area in our heads it just
seems like a long view it was like the
main like the downtown project well I'm
going into town like it's that it's long
view you know but when we do have like
our we're kind of a big small town you
know you know that all the surrounding
areas
I have I mean I remember obviously like
I hated that there was a lot of me
hating the rain in Pacific Northwest
because of a skateboarder yeah and so
I'm just like I'm walking outside all
the time and I'm complaining about it
and like you can't get your grit you're
bored wet because it just sucks it up
and rest the bearings and water logs
your tack and all these things but I
don't know I I was trying to think of
you might remember to was there like a
time in your life that you were like
switched from no I don't know I feel
like there was a time where I like oh
you know what like I I just didn't even
realize it but over the last six months
I've become to love where I live
well yeah after high school everyone
moved away or went away and yeah I know
I stayed here a month no I did a couple
years LCCC but you know I don't I do
think like then I was like well like why
am I here you know everybody's gone
there not a lot of those people came
back and I was like oh wait yeah like
some stayed away and some came back and
I'm like oh okay you know you know what
I mean yeah and then I had relationships
that kept me here or friendships up
whatever whatever and like you know now
I'm here I have a daughter and you know
like well what like yeah California is
nice but we go there to vacation or you
know what I mean but like I like it here
the rain doesn't bother me like you know
call me crazy but I don't like when I
like at night going to bed you know
don't and just crack the window and
listen to the rain at night like that's
peaceful to me and no yeah I'm yeah
that's inconvenient don't but again like
we want to go to the park okay grab your
rain jacking your boots like there's
nothing stopping me from the rain no
it's it's more peaceful to me no yeah
yeah and then all those other places
that you know are out there makes a good
vacation yeah exactly dude I'm so with
you on that I think
and I I just I don't know I I grew you
gotta realize like what sometimes our
vision or our view on things is like we
don't realize we don't see that it's our
view until we like question it like it
like I feel like I went a long time
still like after high school even just
like not realizing that I'd walk around
not liking where I was at or like it
would start raining and I would start
complaining like that's normal or
something and it's like wait like the
raining is so bad like the rain is
happening and then there's my reaction
to you know it's two different things
you mentioned you went to did you go to
LCL CC is every said what classes did
you take Adele CC that's the community
college yeah you know I originally
wanted to ya know I was all over the
board I'm still all over the board but
no I took some classes for like
elementary education but it wasn't my
style I wanted to do something with like
legal not know like uh not criminal
justice but like along the lines of of
that's fine me the word for it know
what's it called when you what am I
thinking
read my mind um reading your mind
criminal justice maybe it's that I don't
know I'm in a space um nope no but then
I realized that I wanted to do a lot of
like this psychology sociology that kind
of stuff like hey yeah I don't after you
know whatever reasoning I went just
wanted to know like why no why are you
the way you are
was she the way she is that kind of
thing so I took a lot of that into my
own no hands and was like okay no I
could have lived in you know in that
psychology class like I took it twice I
just like couldn't get enough of it
no yeah so after that I know but I went
was I was working two full-time jobs at
the time yeah and going to school so I
thought well I'm making a lot of money
right now you know I was what no
nineteen twenty um no so like why go to
school if I'm making all this money
right now you know and then I quit
school well and I don't saved on all
that money and worked and worked and
didn't have time to spend it and then
you know you know quit one job because I
had enough now and then just worked at a
full-time job and
No and then I was like oh wait you know
wait where's school you know and then so
yeah Here I am but no yeah I know I yeah
what was your jumps how long ago was
that like what was the last time that
you took an LCC class like how many
years ago is that six years ago six no
no no that's yeah about that
six years ago seven yeah seven years ago
okay between a good time no I'm not anti
school no it's just not for me
high school is like no I loved high
school have like a [__] college thing
down there but I'm wait I get it
no I am this social choir I couldn't
save my life so that to like book tests
not a thing can't do it
are they nerve-wracking good I could ace
a class no not nerve-wracking I just I'm
just I just I just can't like it just I
seriously cannot yeah I think there's so
many people who like the testers the
class I'm there I'm I aced every single
class but every single test like math
can't do math you give me math I'm dead
like I'm out yeah no oh but um yeah I
just I get feel like I tried so hard but
like the tests you know yeah that kind
of stuff is what got me somethin ya know
I'm out sorry
yeah I'm good money at these two little
minimum-wage jobs you know well
sometimes you got to look at like that's
what's my happiness yeah like what's
money I mean you got it you got a
sacrifice like long-term of course but
if you're able to look anybody this is
this is a little easier on me this is
making my life more more fulfilling I
did I did LCC right after so I graduated
2010 from Kelso and I did LCC was right
afterwards what's that hey what'd you
say what'd you say you wanna fight no
but I did LCC right afterwards and I
honestly did it I was just like young
and I was like I like I don't really
know like I know it's probably should go
to school like I should probably just
keep doing this right like what I
admittedly was just enjoying my life and
in getting drunk and skateboarding and
working
like I was just like let's just keep
doing it because I probably do that so I
did a little bit of LC and it was enough
I think I did two quarters and I didn't
like any of it like a I just it wasn't
for me i but I will say it was it was a
lot of me I wasn't showing up to be the
person that the teacher needed because I
wasn't fully invested I in and I I was
also young and too cocky for my own good
like not being good at math is in a cool
place that I like to be it's very
uncomfortable and so I would just be
like I'm too cool for this math class
now I'm gonna go you know in I don't
know I feel like I I'm glad that I went
to LC I'm glad that I like experienced
it and I don't know just you know a
community college is a great great great
to check out like it like is this for me
because you know sometimes you're like I
don't know if college is really for me
and and spending $40,000 exactly exactly
yeah
but I I do wish that I I mean maybe like
later in life I loved learning about
like psychology and a lot of that same
stuff I'm just a YouTube guy like all
day every day I love listening to like
all kinds of stuff like that um do you
remember anything that like stood out at
that class like that you love learning
or do you member like anything that
hooked you on psychology sorta stuff no
just no no my teacher at the time that
was yeah he was really easy to listen to
no and he was really intriguing he could
even be probably good to sold you on
anything but I know like I just remember
when we're at like where I was at and
that time in my life you know like the
relationship wise but I don't I just
remember like no things learning in the
class like making people who they were
like why people don't act out the way
they do or I know what makes them think
the way no you know just like like
cutting into somebody's mind and you
know which yeah I know it's not probably
for example well but just realizing like
no that's why he is why he is or that's
why she is who she is kind of thing and
I just like I'm obsessed with that yeah
you know as time has gone on and even
over the last couple years like no I
don't want to say I'm obsessed with it
but I'm so intrigued with like no no
like how my mind has developed over the
last few years and like what makes me
who I am like you know people that I
know know I don't know it's crazy it's
so so cool though
you just like try and figure people out
it's like I I hate puzzles but these
kind of it's a very satisfying puzzle
because it's it's very cool to learn
about others and then when you learn
about yourself and you learn like like I
don't know like like who's in the more I
learn about myself like so all be okay
so I have three older sisters yeah and
like I've been fairly alone since like
9:00 but before that like very
detrimental times and like my brain and
my cognitive functions and everything
being born you know zero through seven
zero through eight whatever it may have
been so I have to look at a lot of the
reasons why I do things like my more
feminine side like I've been surrounded
by girls my whole life like her special
note sure of course and also like a lot
of the things that I do are very the
youngest child who doesn't get any
privacy
like I I love my alone time like I'm
like like if I can if I can set up my
space for sure and like make it really
my own in in controller you know cuz
like growing up I said room shared rooms
with sisters and I should ruin through
my mom and in all these things like so
it's it's interesting to see myself as
like I'm a 28 year old grown man but I'm
still kind of just living out being the
youngest child some ways I'm okay with
that like sure yeah but but you kind of
learn learn how you tick and you learn
how other people tick it's just it's
just fascinating like and it makes me it
makes me more compassionate honestly I
think it makes me know like I see people
as their whole life sometimes like that
you know sometimes easy so so angry
drunk guy comes up to you and and you're
just gonna see that situation like
you're just gonna yeah you know and but
but if you can see like there's a reason
why he got drunk exactly you know
there's a reason exactly you know
nothing you could just give everybody
the benefit that now just a situation
but it's it's definitely a thing of
beauty
um Maddie so after after LC he said it
was like six years or so in between to
where now what was your life like in
between then what were you doing what
were your jobs I
worked at a tanning salon for a few
years
no and I know left there and work in a
dental office like I got up front stuff
insurance verifying all like office
assistant kind of stuff and then I know
oh shoot I let's see no okay hmm what
let's see so I just I just worked no for
a few years
no I don't I literally just worked just
working up Emma and I know so okay I
worked I worked at moonlight Bay gotcha
no I don't know I left there and worked
at a dental office and no no I do a lot
of Insurance verifying stuff not and
upfront like office assistant kind of
stuff and then I did no friend god no no
that I knew it was a real really big
into like a car see no not like race
cars but like um like a modified car
scene no and no so I quit my job yeah a
little bit after that and yeah I did not
like photography for a year just for
that not that car club but like local
car clubs in general from Portland to
Seattle so I did a lot of pictures for
like car events no and that occupied my
time for almost a year
you know and then after that I went back
it up don't went back to the dental
office worked a little bit no you know
they're kind of RAD on my brain you're
talking about I actually forgot that you
did the photography thing for a little
bit I'm not a photographer well I mean
you took photos I know I did but I I
don't I don't want to call don't give
myself that title right but did you
enjoy it while you yes I did
yes I did and this side coming out
lately he's totally making me they don't
like reminisce on those days like I
cannot wait to just meet up with old
pals every second just like get their
cars washed and not yeah super fun I met
a lot of cool people that don't end up
some really cool relationships and that
that which no but maybe a few don't my
favorite one is no I
talking to this guy no no no he was
involved with one of the no yeah we've
got the car groups that I was going to
take pictures with or whatever and he
was a four - he is a photographer no and
you know you know I mean I remember
telling my mom like I'm not gonna I'm
drunk I'm gonna drive up to Portland
today no I mean up with this guy and
we're gonna take pictures
no and I look on her face was just like
yeah well who is it and I'm like I don't
I don't know I mean his name's Justin
but I mean he seems really nice
I mean oh I'll be back but whatever yeah
you know no and no she was just I I get
yourself
this wasn't gonna happen not like she
was not she's gonna get murdered by the
nice guy he's a super good friend no but
yeah and we still chat to this day but
you know it's super cool like taught me
you know a bunch of different things I
took pictures of his car like he gave me
some really cool tips and no we all I
mean you know got kind of close after
that and no I mean we're still so good
friends but no and no he's married now
and you know you know has his life set
and I'm you know we I don't know it's
super cool bill yeah you know it was
just funny how like that one like going
out on a limb to go meet up with oh no
with this person who I just trusted that
he was gonna be good because you know he
we had mutual friends up or whatever and
you know super cool but yeah following
three one like intuition let's just try
it
yeah and that's something that you can
have like no maybe you weren't planning
on being a photographer forever being
the most famous photographer but like
it's something like you say bring it up
every summer and enjoy taking pictures
of cars were you into cars no I don't
know much about cards well okay what
what do you like about cars
what in what's your what kind of cars do
you like see here's the thing no mind
you this was a different no time in my
life right I said little bit it still
holds up a big piece of my heart boat I
was really into that no there's a local
so I'm Subaru group in in town in
Longview
no and my friend at the time was always
part about part of this group no no and
so it was
boyfriend let's just put that out there
so we split up
no and you know he you know that went
went one way no I kind of stuck with no
not his car group but no the car group
and kept taking pictures or whatever you
know and so I just kind of like all
those friends soon became mine not and
then as mad as that sounds like yeah
yeah no but yeah yeah so so you know
still to this day you know last weekend
some of us hang out wait no no wouldn't
we all went out for dinner and no drinks
or whatever yeah so no I mean it was
funny just because something that was
just so little at the time no just like
something to do don't go out and take
pictures for one weekend
whatever whatever no and then what that
was at least like six or seven maybe
eight years ago no n-no yeah yeah yeah
we're all still in the cars but we're
all like well no some of us are married
up some of us I've kids Oh some of us
have moved away but still make the time
do don't get together you know every so
often I think that's a really cool thing
about community I really like to mention
that word you know because it has
different meanings like it expands its
me yeah and I think like it's cool
because you know this is six seven years
ago and it still is a community that it
kind of exists to you
look you die you guys got you get
together and and hang out I I really
like to encourage people to like you
know in a small town a lot of times you
think that you need to find what
everybody else is doing and do that but
you can start where you're at you know
like I'm sure I have a Subaru and I like
Subarus like maybe there's a Subaru Club
I have a yeah they may have stuff like
that now but I think it's meetup.com
me it's not it's not where you meets
angles yeah but it's a I did it I did it
to join a book club actually in
Vancouver sure and it was a it was super
cause super glad I did it but yeah I
think encouraging people to do things
like that like if you have an interest
and there's people you're like I'm
nervous to meet them but like yeah we do
share a common interest we can just
start by talking about Subarus you know
ya know funny thing they do is yeah you
know I know you know a young kid came to
you and you know making his coffee and
he was on his fence growing on his phone
you know waiting and I was like hey you
know is that like are you trying to like
a blog
is that a bug I know and he just looked
at me know and know what he was like
what no no I got is that an o2 or no for
and he's like wait what wait you just
like it's like is it a no - or is it a
no for no and he was like what would you
have won and I'm like give me like you
know he's like no well how do you know
about that and I was like yeah yep a
long story but it just like totally got
kind of off garden yeah so we got to
chatting a little bit and you know he
just you know we don't I don't like so
you know like what's your story like how
do you know how did you know about that
and I think it's kids probably like know
maybe 21 so super well I don't like
fresh fell into the scene that I feel
like I should be a veteran in but yeah
so it was super cool they're just gonna
don't see his eyes light up like oh my
gosh somebody like knows what I am you
know what I mean yeah yeah because you
you can you can pull somebody out of
their stuff sometimes like not that he
was like just you know I hate on social
media sometime but just because he
that's so cool and you're like we have a
common ground for sure
let's start there yeah I think that's
always a powerful thing like even if
strangers for sure but even if it's like
a co-worker somebody that you just don't
think I have I don't think I know I
don't think I've ever met a stranger no
I don't I don't I'm just no I'm just
nobody's asked I think everyone's my
friend I mean I know this people who
don't like me you don't but I like know
I will I'll be friends with anybody like
it's just ya know I don't know like if I
know ya idea I think you know you're the
same way don't worry
I mean you I mean you'll talk to anybody
you'll be friends anybody right yeah
that's that I can yeah I don't know do
you remember can you think of like how
that started or I always try to like my
mom is so that's how I am yeah every
time we'd go into a grocery store she'd
know like she'd know somebody or I'm
like oh my god shoes that have Q shoes
on I'm like okay well that's where I get
it so yeah anybody anybody I mean no
just no I don't know I just a little
like what's you can't never have too
many friends right yeah I can't
you I mean I think I don't think so I
mean I know I have a small circle a
really small circle no I'm really tight
with but I don't I mean like there's
nothing wrong with knowing somebody in
right you know there's different like
levels and stages they're doing it's
okay that's something that I that I'll
definitely have like learned as I've
gotten older like yeah like you know the
the mindset that we have I'm like this
is what a friend does this is what a
friend does and it you know as you get
older sometimes it's like like my
childhood best friend yeah right well
well no I think it could still be
friends in a lot of ways like it's like
you know you see him you haven't seen
him in a year and you're still super
excited to see them like they're still
your friend they're still whatever like
yeah but there's also your group of
friends that it's like hey I haven't
talked in a couple weeks what's going on
like are you still good you know
whatever it's a you have to like learn
that not all of your friends and
friendships and relationships are all
the same across the board you kind of
like find different ones but I really
like that about you and I think that's
super cool that you treat everybody as a
friend you see you don't see think
anybody is a stranger no I know and I
just got I sweat no I don't I had
friends it no it's that by themself at
lunch no I know I had friends it around
the basketball team and friends that you
know what I mean you know that were in
freakin band nerds whatever some of
those were the coolest people but I'm
just not I just don't have like go like
that one no I don't know I'll be friends
with anybody
everyone's yeah yeah I guess I feel like
everyone's got something to offer
someone else no that's what I think I
definitely think the same thing I think
knowledge is power and everybody has
something different they can teach you
everybody everybody that you talk to you
it's just waiting to teach you something
you don't know like you know so much
stuff I don't know yes so much I might
know I'm I know stuff you don't know but
like haha life is cool like you know in
the past I've been really not really bad
you know me I don't but really bad yeah
like talking to respond like that was
that was one of my 2020 goals
no no it's talking no don't are not
talking to respond but like just talk
like a conversational but I want to
listen and not be like you know coming
up with what I'm gonna say when you're
done talking
you know what I mean right that's where
I'm at that's that's actually like a
difficult thing to do like when you know
there's a lot of effort yeah do you have
any recommendations for anybody who like
might notice like oh maybe I do just
wait for my chance to talk because I
have my I myself I've even heard my
first some of the first podcast I'd be
like oh my god I was just like well like
that's part of conversing though right
right you know we're not like you say
something up and I'm like oh yeah oh
yeah well I you know yeah but like if
yep if you're like really talking about
something you know in and you say
something you might spark something of
mine but you know just like hang for a
sec like let you finish instead of like
oh oh yeah well I have this too or
whatever but like yep you learned up you
learn so much more about by giving them
the extra couple minutes or seconds or
whatever just to finish what they're
saying and then you'll process you know
don't yeah because there's honestly been
times where like I'll chat with someone
for however long and no alright well
catch you next time you know like have a
good day you know and you're like wait
what like what you know have you ever
had that well we're not like not like a
mind blur but don't like what it like
okay I felt like I totally just rushed
them through that conversation cuz I was
so busy like trying to catch up or like
tell them about me you know sorry no
it's not about me like I want to hear
about you right like you know what I
mean have you ever done that no yeah I
do totally get that I know sometimes I
think that sometimes I think that like
my brain anyway like social media Allah
this might be a stretch but okay so
sometimes so say I just posted or say
it's a I'm I'm famous on social media
I'm so popular I'm the coolest guy ever
in social media and like I post everyday
everybody knows what I'm up to today
it's like everyone's like oh yeah Jake's
he had cornflakes
you know you don't yeah but you did what
was it last year and you shared it yeah
yes I am I'm on my high horse on
Facebook I like when you run into people
you know you want to know what they're
up to
right you don't know about the car they
just bought no or the disco
whatever yeah see I do pay attention I'm
a scroll too much you know that was a
good no it's a good eye opener yeah okay
sometimes where we're trying to hold
everything remember everything from
their Facebook we're trying to you know
you see I think no the the person who
you meet in person the person who you
talk to like whether you know about
their past or whether you know about
them or whatever like I think just
giving them a blank slate to just have
that conversation there and just like
not assume that they know this thing you
know like like if you just like I said I
had cornflakes reckless like I can't
walk up to everybody and yeah in the
back I have in the back of their mind
like hey you know I had cornflakes for
breakfast this morning
weird but so many people and you know
that so so many people are that way yeah
no yeah no yeah I don't know I don't
like it
yeah it's it's uncomfortable but I think
it's something that we have to like no
social media is a weird thing man but
it's a good thing if you use it for the
right reason definitely
what do you how do you manage your
social media use like like what what are
you who do you follow on social media
that you like following that's not just
like scrolling stuff or not see like I
know like on my facebook know Instagram
is just for scrolling
no no but Facebook like friends yeah
friends family you know people that I I
know or of like know that I have no not
that just like oh I know
no it's her because of her well I don't
that's on Facebook it's work for me but
like Facebook Facebook is for people
people I don't that I want to keep in
touch with but don't see or I don't know
yeah it sounds too cliche but we didn't
know like my daughter just started her
first ballet class and I've got lots of
friends that don't live around here that
I don't want to start like a 12 person
group chat know you know I didn't know
like family that lives away from your
well so where I can post it on there and
then they'll all see it maybe they'll
see it no no you know what I mean know
what or do I look for recommending
okay she only got anyone anybody have
like a cool DJ they can DJ wedding
whatever and then everybody responds
with you know Carlos Carlos Carlos good
now lately I'm like yeah yeah you know
you know I think no so I like social
media yeah yeah because no I get all it
can be negative because you're
constantly you don't like well if you
have it you know like your your your
scrolling your scrolling and then like
no I don't know like everybody's lives
are perfect on Instagram no they just
you know or on social media
they just are I mean my life is perfect
on Instagram right look at it go look at
my page like I'm happy as [__] but and I
really I really am but there are days
where I'm just like oh they're they're
not my days yeah you know human I am I
am human but like you know you don't
know like you know especially like
business-wise you know there's I like
Instagram for inspiration or like ideas
or no you know it's good for like
advertising or like getting your know
your business yeah you know just yeah
it's you know so social media can be
such a powerful thing like super
powerful like in a super good way but it
can also be not super good yeah I think
learning to control it like we like
people around our age we kind of like a
road I always say we road like the way
we're just shredding it's so cool like
the new thing well yeah razor what
that's the thinnest phone I've ever seen
in my whole life it's so mind-blowing
and they have the next one and it's so
cool but but as we get older like this
is you know I I'm probably over overly
dramatic about the subject far too often
but for me I think like as a human
species like we've never experienced
anything like this before and I think
that taking a look at like where are we
at in history and like what's you know
how can we take these cool exciting
things and get older later in life and
start to manage them and make them make
our lives better so you said that you
use Instagram for inspiration I totally
love Instagram for inspiration
so you
also have a wonderful bail denim coat is
it bail denim Co company do we say yeah
it's junk it's just Vail denim male
denim no you know it's just it's just
don't just feel denim so I had a
daughter in 2016
her name is Cove like CoV veil like Vail
Colorado no I love me - no me - it's
beautiful yeah but you know you know she
no she won't
she was yeah no no no I don't not quite
one no and I I was a stay-at-home mom no
until she was almost too but um she
don't she I had cool ripped jeans I love
jump distressed no you know loved
distressed jeans I probably wore him
everyday you know and I wanted her never
bear cuz who doesn't want to match right
on their little baby girl so I went
online and I was like absolutely not no
I am NOT okay I can't spend up
nor will I spend well don't like $50 on
a pair of ripped jeans like my grandma
would have a fit yes and no so so I know
you know got a pair of jeans that she
already had don't you know and I don't
took my ghetto ass kitchen scissors to
them and you know whatever and I made
myself a pair for her
nope yeah and I know you know social
media I posted a picture of her because
she was so damn cute and no and you know
a couple people wanted I'm selling I
mean I would make up you know you know
whoever wanted a pair and then I was
like I'm going in the hole no so then I
was like I went I was uh no no yeah so I
would make those and then no sure enough
I was like I can't
yeah I don't know you know like but just
buy my coffee survival mode like
whatever no and then it got to be more
than that and you know eventually had a
lady named Sean you know who owned dope
like a brick-and-mortar kids clothing
for no income
Washington's yeah but she don't she
reached out to me don't to see if I
wanted to sell you know you know my
little denim stuff there at her store
and I was like yeah that would be like
super cool but I didn't know like this
was just like a side gig no no I mean
you know no you know and so I don't I
said yeah put it in her store no they
sold I mean a lot more than I thought
and so I was like holy cow and so then
long story long I know but what I
started doing like women's apparel up
cycled and distressed denim nope and
sold those at a local shop in Longview
no and you know they don't that don't
yeah I probably made no well I probably
made of like a few hundred pairs of
shorts shorts denim jackets or whatever
that summer no that was probably two
summers ago and so I was like holy crap
like I know they don't like this is so
cool but I'm like no a little
overwhelmed you know yeah and so at this
point I'm where I'm working part-time
yeah
and doing this feel denim staff know and
being a single mom know so it was super
cool it paid for like all of our you
know I mean I helped pay a lot of our
bills but no no no now we've even gone a
little bit farther and do you know and
we don't have anything in any stores Oh
which is kind of a weight off my
shoulders but we launched our website no
veil denim calm and we do everything
through that know so I still am taking
advantage of my three-year-old napping
and when she goes to bed I don't go to
bed no for a little while and no my yeah
my entire kitchen dining room areas got
no scraps and fabric and a sewing
machine and a cutting board and it'll
you know and I know I'm losing my mind
the thing you hang on you're a backdrop
a backdrop and it's got a ring light and
it's like you know like I'm just a bunch
of no no it'll it's my little my little
shop so no it's a fun adventure I've got
a lot of local girls who also do like
homemade hee
no yep you don't you know small business
stuff they wear really tight circle no
and I know it's a super fun adventure
super cool I met a lot of cool people
through doing that too but yeah it
sounds like you found another like
community too yeah yeah I'm all about
finding little communities you know yeah
I love that I think it's super important
especially I didn't realize that until
now yeah community hunter yeah well hey
whenever when nobody's your stranger
every surprise yeah yeah me too do that
so when you get in spots
okay so I've I've distressed a pair of
jeans and to myself I I feel like I've
definitely used kitchen scissors for
sure but I've used hand saw like you
know like no well yeah back and forth
hand saw that seemed to be my go-to but
I that's that's the extent of my
distressing of denim well what else do
you do like what are some you not to
give away your secret tips or anything
but yeah yeah great job I graduate
graduated up to no well no well no well
my stepdad no used to so yeah make all
his own clothes ski jackets no whatever
like he know he's the king of the sewing
machine know so I borrowed his sewing
shears and I borrowed his sewing machine
no it's currently in my kitchen no and
no he is very supportive and he's all
all you know well for me making this
little business a new thing but no oh he
hasn't asked for his sister's back yet
he knows where is that what he knows to
use it yeah yeah you know he is going
with this no oh yeah yeah he is with all
the sewing shears yeah I graduated up to
those you know and I don't I have a
little bit of a everything I do is hand
like hand distress hand up cycle
whatever no so no I'm not China so I
can't like bust out yeah yeah but um I
don't use a cheese grater or the razor
anymore like I didn't know I'm a little
bit more legit but yeah it's super fun
no we graduated fried cheese grater it
mines me and when I'm in high school
every time I could
denim I'm like oh my gosh Ramona needs
to get like the tweezers and like flick
each thread over oh yeah and it's no
exam and it's so funny like I mean it's
cool because in our minds we're like I
cared about this thing and I'm wearing
it and like really good nobody's gonna
like super notice those details but
there are some people that will and it
is satisfying to you sure I really I've
always liked customizing my my wife
really what's customizing my always love
that's another thing to wait we don't
know like each thing I do don't there's
not another thing like it like no we
recently got don't know started like a
pre-order in it's funny because when I
was packaging them up a couple weeks ago
I thought of you know when you're you're
you matter line or no ours with that
says it's okay to not be okay and I was
like oh my gosh remember that sweatshirt
I wanted so but none of our size is a is
it no is the same like we have that same
print to go on denim middle or flannels
or whatever but it's not like I don't
know like I won't sell something that
looks like something else no like they
all have to be you know like unique and
one-of-a-kind really that's because so
no I don't know I thought that was super
cool but yeah yeah I really like that I
think that's a very cool business model
and I'm sure that that like the
interactions that you have like when you
sell to the person like so do you if you
meet up with people like you get to see
them face to face when you give it to
them so now you're online but ya know
was that like no I work full-time yeah
and sometimes more and I don't have like
I want to have time to map to me every
single person and we put like a little
personal touch up you know inside each
package but it's not realistic for me to
like yeah you know dry I mean well I'll
if you yeah no I yeah I get what you're
saying yeah cuz you got to start out
like that sometimes like it because I
was just thinking with you man deliver
every baggage no and there's like hug
every person that I think when they open
it click it every thank you whatever
yeah
No yeah I think they're giving you a hug
that they accept it they understand it's
like an individual original piece I
think that's supercool fashion-wise just
even before distressed denim and stuff
when did you get into fashion do you
have anything that like not know so it's
kind of you mentioned earlier like no
you had a lot of sisters no three that's
a lot no you have like a different
feminine side well I grew up with two
brothers know so I'm like vans jeans and
like a ter like a hoodie or crewneck or
whatever your pants right now to you by
the way no yeah that's the dopest girl
and so so I don't I know I'm not super
girly no by any means and so I'm not
really like into like know like like
fashion hmm but no yeah I don't know no
like I I don't know I just I just kind
of roll with it like whatever's yeah
you've know like I don't own a dress you
probably never see me in a dress no but
um no no I don't I just think like look
and over the last couple years with like
my mental health space - or mental
headspace held space whatever know it
like you know you know you can express
so much don't like don't think about
when you go somewhere and you like
notice somebody's outfit hmm right it's
cool know like oh no he has school shoes
or she has a cool hat whatever like why
not like express yourself through what
you're wearing right like oh that's a
super cool sweatshirt that says it's
okay not to be okay I want one like I
want it no I want people to know you
know what I mean or like whatever we
upcycled know oh like oh that's super
cool denim bastard just whatever like
you can express yourself through what
you're wearing and it's just a super
cool message whether or not it says
anything we're all kind of like it's
kind of like WWE sometimes in the real
world right by that I mean like we're
all kind of walking around like we all
know like you know so you walk into a
tap house right and like before you
notice anybody fashion you all kind of
know like hey these people everybody in
this room they have their own [__] we
all have our own [__] of all you know
learn through different ways and we all
have different paths and we'll have
different futures we have different
interests but like there's this common
like WWE like but we
to pretend we don't we don't have to
like yeah we'll have to make sure that
we're all but I think for me fashion has
been always been cool because it kind of
like puts a little flag like a sticks
out like with WWE it's like like a real
UFC fighter sort of thing it's just we
can break out of that thing like someone
who would not expect you or I to talk to
them and we're like hey man that's a
cool jacket and I'm like oh shoot and
then you know you break him out of their
head like you were talking about that
with the super with that guy like yeah
you know it took him a little bit he was
like stumbling but then you have you
open up the conversation so I think
that's super freaking cool um excuse me
so I want to go back to Vail Colorado
selfishly just because I think it's no
okay so I used to work this show
I never skied up there or snowboard it
up there but we would stay in the cabin
with in Vail in Vail like actually up in
there so you land in Denver and it's
like what two hours up the something
like a couple hours about that yeah it's
been a few years but we have essentially
my production team we would stay in the
cabin and there's like the ski lifts
through the front yard like okay you can
go on the balcony I'm like hit someone's
shoe no doubt who's on the ski lift in
it oh my gosh so I haven't actually like
seen the whole the whole beauty that I
feel like other people have but it's
very it's not he's done it's better yeah
it's very you know like got like a
classy feel it's not it's like right out
of a movie when I went like every time
the one time you know I've only been
there one time that's fine hey I had
that much impact I've only been there
like two three times I think but yeah
yeah so um when did you go to hell with
how old are you when you went there I
was 24 yeah no 24 no and did you go to
like the the town and stuff there right
yes I have family in Colorado okay but
we don't we met we went for air look
like look we got I think about like
about a week know and uh and we got
closer to Denver know like outside a
veil between Denver and Bill No yeah and
what we just went for the mountain to
the mountain because I mean you have to
go there if you're there right
and by the way we did miss the
Kardashian clan by like two or three
days no I was kind of bummed about that
devastating wait what were they do they
know skiing like they've rented the
mountain that's a regular thing for them
no apparently I know I'll just name my
next kid Kanye or something no I'm down
no I'm a huge supporter of Connie No all
right lately lately okay what do you
think about screw Valen screw Vail okay
I'm with you okay so I think my opinion
on Kanye I'm just gonna bullet past you
I'm sorry no I think I've had this some
good conversation with Shay Lee's dad
yeah about this like I think I think
like oh it's coming either with it here
for or you're not
yeah I'm so here with I will say I give
I've always given the benefit of the
doubt like I actually rewatched risa I
watched the Taylor Swift documentary and
I saw the scene where he like
interrupted her and I saw it as like an
older person now no dad is so messed up
what he did but back then I remember
like like oh he was you know it's no big
deal it's just whatever like didn't
realize but I don't know I feel like I
have still grown with him and so what
he's doing listener if you don't know
he's been doing a kind of transition to
all of his music into like more worship
music he does his Sunday service thing
now it's I think that like in the music
world in like the pop culture world I
think that over the next few years I
think that Kanye is going to have like a
very positive impact angry and change
but I know I guess I don't follow
no hon I kinda have just seen like what
I see on youtube it yeah yeah I know I
agree I think like no it's hard enough
yeah you know it's hard to like good you
get a grasp on somebody that's had no no
no not death not that he's had a [__]
and they yeah negative impact on my life
yeah but he's just not kind of known for
no being no Kanye you know you know that
I'm not like all about him and it's you
know you know and he's got I think like
we talked about earlier know um you know
who you know or like who you knew know
like time goes on in know like know like
as much as we can say
oh yeah I've changed or don't like I'm
I'm different now in whatever ways other
people are capable of doing that - yes
no so and it's hard
yep it's you know to like accept or
recognize and be like oh I'm you know
like I just that they're changing or
well whatever like no other people are
capable of being somebody else no like
they are capable of change and bettering
themselves and I really think know that
no it's kind of like religion our
politics like no you don't you know it
can be II don't like your either no you
either are or you aren't not here for
you know you know I keep stopping there
no no so yeah I really I really think
that like you know he's gotten a grasp
on like who he was who he wants to be
and like who he is like who he's going
to be right and I don't I think that
it's less about like oh like you know
his all about me I think it's not you
know he wants to reach out and like let
other people have that chance to be
creative and like like a positive
outreach and be who they're gonna be or
just have like a more positive no effect
on know does that make sense no no Tony
because I'm somebody with that much of a
know hollowing yeah like yeah yeah like
he has yeah no yeah forward for where
he's at like in his celebrity Fame or
whatever no you know he's got like the
know like he's in the perfect position
like he's up on that pedestal on his
pedestal but he's gonna use it for a
more positive right yeah but I I think I
think it could be something I really do
i I genuinely do - I I mean I understand
I get my position I have always been
like a Kanye family more they do no
wrong but I I really do respect you know
it seems like I listen to more
interviews with him in the last year and
like I used to listen to interviews with
him often like you know beat-making like
way back in amuse you know and he's
always been he's he's a definitely a
different part like you know we see him
and he's confident onstage and he's like
says these things in his lyrics but like
yeah when you had conversation with him
or people would interview with him like
he's not a super comp like he would he
stumble overs words in these sort of
things he'd be very misunderstood to
totally human and then I feel like he
has he's he's helped himself out over
the last few years and he's a you know
I'm sure I'm sure
Kim and in their life and everybody
other life has like greatly helped him
having children growing up he just like
he's shedding his ego in his life he's
learning how to he's learning that he
does have like one of the biggest
impacts of like like I am a god yeah
there yeah he's like you know it's
interesting on he says I am a god or I'm
I am the most popular like but it's if
you know I mean outside of ego like he
literally does have like one of the
biggest followings like yeah he has the
power to influence many lives and I
think that's so so incredible that he's
taking that now and you know trying to
trying to do good for it wherever that
leads I think I'll be super interest
absolutely no absolutely yeah I'm I'm
intrigued have you ever seen Connie live
no I mean videos yes but not like no I
like I like Kanye about but I've never
been like yeah I don't know I'm I'm not
anxious I'm anxious to see where this
takes him I think I'm very curious like
I like I need to know yeah
good I'm like yeah cuz I feel like with
pop culture I love pop culture but it
you know we have the this is gonna sound
tinfoil hat for sure we have like the
government who like controls these
things in the news and they control
obviously like the business stuff but
you know the leaders of pop culture
control our everyday interactions like
like what like what we're wearing what
we're influenced by what we're how we're
talking to each other the slang we use
the you know like I like Kanye is from
Chicago and like oh wait he's never
Chicago but like there's slang that me
as some white dude in Kelso Washington
wouldn't never even use in my daily
conversation but when I listen to a
bunch of Kanye's caviar caviar I mean I
always do a lot of VeggieTales you know
so with those beats rapping about the
hair yeah but it's cool to you know it's
cool to see that people realize you know
like oh I do have an impact
like like what what I what I do is made
okay and what I do influences other
people to do you know in really as long
as a positive impact no that's what I'm
about right like yeah yeah and it's yeah
I know I know that he has the potential
no I mean look at what he's done
no and other is you know right I
definitely I know he has the potential
but I'm I just want to see what he's
gonna do I'm sure my seat with that [__]
yeah I'm like I'm ready and I mean in
Kim's doing a lot of really cool stuff I
again I don't know too much about that
site but she's like helping people who
are wrongly accused and yeah jails and
jail prison sentences and moms a
Kardashian like she's worships yes
pretty indication yes no I know it's my
but like like the music I listen to I
don't I don't live that lifestyle nor do
I want to don't you know but like I just
I like to live it through them that's
not who I am or what I you know know so
that's just a clear though I am rap
caviar ya know I feel I have I have so
many different moods where it's like
yeah like I can be at the gym I'm like
in my headphones it's just like the most
hardcore like yeah and then someone I
take my headphones off because someone
talks to me okay yeah you know it's like
I'm representing this it's know we all
have human emotions and an outside of
the lyrics you know you got to be
careful with constant lyrics but yeah a
lot of times it's the feeling that the
song in the in the words give you just
lock it especially driving man like
sometimes you just gotta feel like a
holler when you're driving yeah you got
to go ham you do you so I want to talk
about I always like talking about like
digging a hole in change no I think I
already mentioned something similar but
do you have a point in your life or a
memory that pops up that you can you
know that you changed your view on
something you grew out of an old view or
no this is a tough one
start me like give me like like yeah I
got you okay
let's have some ideas but I okay let's
see where I meant let's see where I
changed my view obviously like it like
simple easy one just or they are
conversation like my view on rain
obviously I was just like oh yeah I
should I should appreciate that sort of
thing because that's what gives you the
green grass but um I think I think he
stumped myself even on this Mady what
what a terrible yeah it's not that hard
but but I thought I feel like no yeah
like yeah I don't
I changed my view no no no like on I
don't know like there's so many areas
that this could take me mm-hmm
[Music]
no well let it sit you want to let it
just sit in the background if we come in
why yeah yeah okay
let's see yeah okay how oh okay wait I
do have one what was the areas that you
changed this could spark one when you
became a mother did was there like yeah
you know because I'm obviously there's
the inn and you could talk about the two
like I've always thought thought okay
okay here's here's one I change I'm
following into okay okay stumbling over
being a host here I'm sorry
so I imagine um I used to be very like
no instant to joke about like birth like
it like if you're like in the room like
like would you want to be in there and
there's just kind of like running guy
joke of like I don't want to see that
I'm not gonna see that tore up just like
terrible like an open you know it's just
like this weird joke that guys honestly
don't approach farther than that joke
like it seems like we like keep it there
and we keep it like this
this joke between us but I have like
over the last couple years like I'm
trying to like you know figure out where
like like do I want to be a father and
you know turns out yes I do and like
these different things and I have opened
my mind essentially to I think that
instead of it being this like oh that's
an intense situation I don't want to be
in the room with the screaming and stuff
like I in my head I'm like that seems
like probably the most beautiful moment
in a life like that
that seems if you think about it yeah
that's what I saw yeah well
well you know it's a it's what we you
know what we know and what we've heard
and what it's just like that's just what
it is like what what you said oh when
you think about you know being enough in
their delivery room out when someone's
giving a baby you just know like
everybody talks about the worst you know
no but well I like when I was in the
delivery room I know
well like okay so my water broke earlier
that day no no and it was a it wasn't
what everybody thought like this no no
I'm not like completely honest like
everything oh you'll know you'll know
when your water breaks and I was like
okay well know if your mom and if you're
not a mom this might just be not your
thing but no like we know when you're
pregnant weird [__] happens just just
that so I was like oh I think I just
kind of like what my pants a little no
and I was at my mom's and son my
daughter's car seat you know I started
two weeks left
no so I went inside you know change
whatever came back out and I was like
whatever not that but it was like okay
no okay so I got no I told my mom
whatever whatever long story long she's
like you need to go in no your water
broke and I was like no it didn't no
like look at me I might be like whatever
I'm whatever so she know so I get in the
shower I throw some sweats on I
literally throw my sweats on grab my
phone and go like I'm annoyed right I'm
like 38 weeks [__] pregnant don't
you're a noise like taking me to the
damn hospital though because I had a
freaking little accident I don't have
time for this like I've got stuff to do
before this baby comes whatever so but
she got she's like oh yeah are you
hungry you know and I'm like no like in
and out let's do this no yeah well so I
don't eat no it's like it is 4:03 p.m.
no because my birthday is April 3rd or 3
you don't so I know
yeah it's 403 when I get to st. John
that no I walk in no look my mom like
walks out I mean she's like my
daughter's water broke I think and I'm
like oh like you know it's not funny to
me like my water didn't frickin break oh
my god like the movie said I don't like
all my friends said like y'all no no
okay
oh that didn't happen so yeah so I got I
get it I get in no I go to the bathroom
well I go sit in the waiting room nope
they call me back and they're like oh
your water broke and I'm like I'm
getting me right like what like that's
not what they said it was gonna happen
yeah yeah and so I go back yeah yeah
left and like I said I brought my phone
no that's all I brought don't like threw
it in my pocket and what No
so I get in the freaking room and no I'm
like I have nothing no and I'm just like
did you have like an overnight bag
packed and stuff before it like you
don't plan on hiking that's nothing
right no so I don't plan no like I just
know I just go so um that always works
better for me what went well like what
when I'm rushed up and I I do bet the
better was like yep we don't get
everything no time yeah yeah you just
have to do so yep yeah and so I get in
there and get my got my gown on whatever
and no like I was up Diane I was dilated
just to like a 3 or 4 so so you don't
you have to get to 10 right so and I
felt I felt nothing like I was just more
like bored sitting there you know so my
mom was there and my mom's friend was
there no yes yeah and she got she's in
there something's uh I told her when I
go in you have to be there like I want
you know you know you know as a nurse
yeah I don't I want you I just want to
want you in there friend for comfort
well whatever you're my birth coach and
she would draw all the birth classes
with me and it was super fun but um I'm
so good at making a long story even
longer so we get into four five six I
kind of get stuck there so so that end
up they know they induced me to get
things moving you know and no nothing
like I admitted like a seven not feeling
anything or not not contracting so I'm
like is this right yeah I don't like I
literally I don't I don't feel like
anything and so then I get to like an 8
and I'm getting uncomfortable at this
point like just starting to get like
kind of stomach cramp II and then like
eight and a half nine well I
oh they'll keep checking you yeah see
how not further dilated you are and not
at this way I'm like at a nine and I'm
like I have to got I need to up to like
go use the bathroom and they're like oh
no you can't am I go no well yeah okay
this where my mom probably won't like
this part of the podcast was like no I'm
probably gonna like [__] my pants like I
need to go to the bathroom real quick
no and they're like okay lay down but
we're down the check here real quick you
know and so I lay down and I'm like oh
my god like I need you not to go to the
bathroom like and to go back a little
bit like I when I went in there I was
but I wanted to epidurals one in the
front one in the back I was not gonna
feel this right so I didn't feel
anything so I totally miss up miss the
window for the epidural oh you know
because like I'm not earning so I don't
need it right yeah so at this point I'm
like yep I need to go to the bathroom
whatever so yeah they sent me back up
now okay you know you we're gonna go get
a doctor
whatever whatever I think you're about
ready and I'm like Restless at this
point you know I can't sit still like I
need to go to the bathroom so no the
doctors yeah couldn't they came in a
couple nurses came in and literally if
you've not ever been in that room you
know it is so incredible within like
five seconds they had that hospital room
turned into like it looked like a
spaceship like lights came out of the
corners no I'm not kidding it was insane
there was like yep seven people in there
and I was like pushing hey I just yeah
like I just know like I just went like I
just that I didn't I didn't just want it
and I was like my body just knew what to
do yeah it was incredible and I got
super lucky and I think it only took me
like maybe four six pushes and she was
out but you know it was up it was insane
like it was something that I'll always
remember
I don't I mean I got hurt I mean didn't
feel good but like yep you're bringing
another life into the world like whoa
don't it's a it's a it is a it was weird
because like what
I had her and they don't they later
write on my chest I was like none of
that matters I get hurt for a minute but
I was like they just went away yeah and
you're like oh my god like this is my
this is my little human yeah you know no
it was the most like and I don't know
from a dad's perspective but like as a
parent like you created that right no
it's it's so it's really cool and it's
so no no I don't know the word for it
like if you don't want to be a parent
fine like no there's other things that
you can you know you know you know that
I mean not like your life your purpose
is no somewhere else so yeah if you but
if you are a parent no it's I don't know
it's incredible I can't think of any
other words to like describe that moment
and then you got you bring the baby home
and you're like all of your priorities
change
right yeah like you don't know you know
you can't run you can't just run into
the minute my real quick and grab know
like you know you know you know what I
mean like you know you you have this
life that you have to keep alive like
it's not about you know like you know
you're tired you're hungry yeah okay
well this one comes first so yeah it's
quite an adjustment but and yet as any
parent well that could probably agree
but you know I know like I don't know
what I did before like it just is like
that's just she's just my life now and I
wouldn't change it for anything that's
because I had so much more well more
energy you know before before I was a
mom but I don't like I'd rather be tired
know every single day
then not have no no like I'm just bored
without her right yeah it's the best and
like whatever you do yes they do do you
know no like you just adapt and you know
that's a cool thing it's really just a
mini run around oh my gosh oh and -
she's awesome she's so fun yeah that's
fantastic I you know it's a cool thing I
very much like I like trying to take
myself on the outside of situations that
I'm that I'm in so like like my friends
you know like I don't have any kids but
I I have my friends over the years
you know like and I've I've thrown rocks
at buildings in drink at the age of 13
with these boys you know like like we've
been total turds but to see them like
you know have some see we start having
some serious conversations like to see
them get nervous to see them like talk
about how much they love their daughter
now and yeah how much that you know to
see a man or a woman change so you know
they're especially through to childbirth
to raising a kid is so cool and I'm glad
that I know I I think I just wanted to
put a pin in it because I I think that I
used to because I didn't have my stuff
figured out I didn't have like in my
head it was like the thought of kids was
like I would like to push it away cuz
normally I don't know you know like I
want to get it away but I'm being able
to like look at it and see like you like
your friends who you know very well just
change as people and men and women and
and just it's cool
life is life is fantastic yes Maddie I
would like to if you'd like to I would
like to talk to you about Tourette's I I
don't think that I know anybody else
with threats but I I think that as far
as like education goes you are fantastic
with it as far as being kind to people
about it I feel like you're great with
that like explain to people what's going
on you've probably had a lot of moments
where in correct me if I'm wrong it
seems like you may have had a lot of
moments where someone may not understand
it like they've never been around
something with Tourette's and they might
like like say something or they might
like look at you strange like they don't
know what's going on and it seems to me
um I don't I don't know if sure tell me
if I'm wrong but it seems to me like
you're not kind of personal but with
lucky looking at you know like you're
like you're probably hard but wound up
whatever when I was younger I thought my
mom no no and still to this day is that
is about the most supportive person know
I've ever know like she I wouldn't know
nowhere look like I I wouldn't I know I
wouldn't be here I wouldn't know who I
was without her but um she know she's
always been so so what
you know when I when I was like like so
let's say six or seven is when I got
diagnosed but leading up to that know I
have what's called don't like transient
take so no they come and go they know
you know you know yeah they don't stay
you know forever there's always
different ones know so um I know I
started blinking my eyes a lot my mom
was like oh my gosh you need glasses the
teacher thought I needed glasses
whatever or whatever
No so I got glasses it went away no no
so I started clearing my throat
no and then no the teacher my mom my
parents I should say you know my parents
no thought I had a cold or whatever
whatever you know so I you know Michael
went away you know and then the next
thing came no you know and so how long
they thought oh well it's just we're
fixing up fixing the problem because
yeah she got glasses and she stopped
blinking hard or she you know what I
mean oh no but really what we didn't
know is these were the transient kind of
you know of take so and so they would go
away just in good time to no no like
solve the problems no and so then it got
to where it was like no it's a little
bit more than this like a TD ADHD threat
oh no no you know it's all along the
same line oh really
no so ya know so I was diagnosed when I
was about seven no a ton of doctors had
no idea no it was just my age or was
just you know know all those kind of
things and then I saw a specialist like
a neurologist a specialist who
specifically specialized in Tourette OCD
ADHD all these like neurological things
so she diagnosed me know and then you
know going forward
through through that like elementary
school dope
I was on medication for Tourette you got
but it would make my ADHD worse so then
I would stop and I would do something
for a DD no no ADHD but it would exact
the Trix know so at that point towards
like after middle school in middle
school I was like I know like I would be
no I was not myself like I was boring I
was quiet
I was really sluggish no no and that's
that wasn't me no and so I mean don't
know I made the choice my parents let me
make the choice I get for you you don't
well if you don't want to medicate then
don't know and so I was like all right
like I'm out I'm out I'm done like this
is and so after that I was well I was
back to playing soccer and volleyball
and basketball or whatever all the
sports I played no so no you know yeah
so then came in through middle school if
yeah oh man elementary school no and
middle school my mom would meet every
single year with every single one of my
teachers no no and and she would sit
them down and say no this is my daughter
no she has tourette what can we do as a
team to ensure that she has a successful
school year no and no no you know and at
the time I was like oh well you know you
know like here's my mom ya know but well
no and then as I got older know
so in middle school actually no I don't
ever know I would go to every teacher
know and tell them when I got my
schedule and talk with them and be like
okay I'm mad you know I have tried like
I just want to let you know so I don't
come to class the first day and you're
like you know no yep so in middle school
I'm sorry in high school I would do the
same thing and I remember one of my
teachers I was like okay well on the
first day of class I'll let you stand up
and you don't know and like you know and
introduce yourself to the class and I
was like oh okay yes and so I did and
then yeah I would jump I went to school
that's about a lot of the same people
since elementary school so a lot of them
know I mean everyone not everyone knew
me but a lot of people just knew me and
it's just what no and I was friends with
everybody like I just know whatever no
stranger and so in high school I got
like honest to god
I was never like know like there were
some [__] no but I was never like
bullied no but you know and I'm so
thankful but I don't but I don't and
maybe it's because I'm just super
confident or maybe I did get Boyd and I
just let it like look like it didn't
know it didn't like get under my skin I
don't know no no no but I know I don't
I do think like you know me being able
to own Who I am and you know because I
had so much support growing up and it
was just like not a thing like no oh you
have tried okay like what's next so like
I have braids in my hair okay you know
what I mean just like why don't like
like it's nice for that the Fertile like
further heads up but at the same time
like okay thanks so but yeah and then in
high school I thought it was it was good
high school was good and same thing with
LCC I let my teachers know that you know
you know here's you know the low down
and I'll be in your class you know and
nobody know you know nobody really had a
problem with it right no and I mean I
know like okay so fast-forward yep do
too much like my early 20s no no this is
where no like I was born I've always
been independent and confident and I'll
do what I want kind of thing but more
that more so in my trunk my 20s is when
I just kind of became my own like know
like I don't need my mom even though I
do need my mom all the time
no yeah yeah but um no there's people
where no so yeah the biggest eye-opener
for me was like I'll go into a store and
people are like you know what I mean
like what is happening over there no you
know it's all just smiling like oh hey
you know and they're like okay like you
know you know I mean I'm sure I give up
get mistaken for you know weirder things
but no like it doesn't bother me is kind
of my vibe so should so it shouldn't
bother you sort of thing I don't know
and if you're curious just ask like the
biggest thing I can say is like I'm here
no no like I know I used to be here to
educate no now I'm just kind of like it
is what it is and I'm still what one day
I want
educate because ignorance is just a lack
of knowledge like they don't know you
know people just don't know know that
ignorance is a land knowledge case you
know but but on the other note you can't
fix you but like some people just don't
get it no some people do not get it they
don't want to maybe look maybe maybe
they can't accept that
I don't know they can't accept you know
like the difference or whatever but yeah
like for me no no matter everyone's got
something yeah but whether you can see
it here and feel it whatever no no you
just know you just have to educate like
people don't like to me like I'm like
how do you not know what it is
no but I've lived with it yeah but
people just don't know so yeah yeah
you're like oh I've trapped no it's just
like a neurological disorder and
whatever I make weird sounds no but no
this is what it is not in 90 percent of
the time like oh no yeah okay no but
like there's that 10% that are like what
yeah you know what I'm like but it's so
cool that they're able to just like you
you're you're friendly and you're open
and you're like hey if this is weird to
you I can explain it real quick but
otherwise that's just yeah what do you
want to know about it not but you're
looking at me so mad I'll tell you yeah
no but young people need updated but a
little bit later in my you know in my
life I felt like I was almost getting
annoyed I think well but under under
stress I don't know lack of sleep if I
eat like crap it gets worse just like
anybody's body right well when you eat
like crap you don't feel good you know
what I mean so no same for me but we
don't like well you know like a little
bit after like my mid-20s I would say I
don't I would no I just wasn't taking
care of myself like well I was I was but
not in the right ways you know and so
yeah like my trip was a little bit worse
no no and so no good I got to a point
where it was almost like angry and
really short patience is that a word
patience patience patience no well I
just you know so if someone would look
at me I'd be like I like do you have a
question you know you know
in my head I'm like God like why are you
peeking through the frickin ass clothes
a cat me we're at Nordstrom Rack not
that ghetto no no some racket no yeah so
but I you know and then when I do when I
was doing that I was like oh no well
where does that get anybody nowhere oh
so now I'm just like you know no no what
now well know that I'm a mom I feel I
feel like my daughter is only 3 but no
no it's never too early to start
no so no no like like yeah well the
other day we know or like not gonna know
so like doctor yeah you know Dino that
kind of stuff doesn't even faze me where
you know you see a guy in a wheelchair
know do you know do you need to explain
no he's just you know you see a lady
with a scarf on and no hair no no like
those things up no those don't need to
be explained
right like it just is you know what I
mean like people just are who they are
no and so like my three-year-old the
other day was I saw a guy in a
wheelchair and she was like mommy how
come he has wheels and I was like Oh
[__] just can't walk in nuts just who
he is
move along didn't bat an eye no you know
it just he just you know you know it
just is or
no my mommy how come like yeah just
little things and I'm Michael that's how
God made him or whatever you know what I
mean and so no little angel and growing
up with me like nope yeah no you know it
hasn't no it has not even come up to her
nope or any of her little friends but
especially her like why does your mom
make that noise you know like you know
it just it just freakin is and she
doesn't even know any different no but I
do have to say no you know you know
Billy Eilish yeah you know where she
don't just sad your little interview on
Ellen and let the world know that she
has Tourette's - did you know oh I had
no idea yeah I cry been obsessed with
your brother Phineas so hold on come yet
we'll come back to Billy Eilish okay but
well covet right my daughter up was
watching that man I was like oh my god
[__] Billy I know shows Tourette's and
she's like what's Tourette's
know
no no those weird noises mommy makes and
she goes hmm
mom want to play Barbies I'm like no
okay so so whatever you know but anyway
like so she knows Billy Eilish and mommy
have Tourette's no and you don't make
fun that's not her key line like you
know you know some new threats yeah I
don't make fun no it just is what it is
so so so at three she already knows like
no you know whatever the difference is
yours color of skin she doesn't even
notice and neither do i why should we
it's just who somebody is okay so yep
but Billy I'll Joe so one a lot a couple
years ago I was in the know the target
parking lot changing my daughter's
diaper in the backseat no and there's a
big where like Mercedes van that pulled
up no and no I was like oh that's weird
and the girl that got out of it was like
totally she she was a really cute girl
but like her swag didn't matte like no
no I don't know how to explain it she um
she had a really crazy nope
but like authentic vibe about her but I
was like whoa like oh not a bad thing
but I was like no like she's somebody
like who is that
no and then a guy got out and like -
like it don't look like parents but they
all had name tags on no like like little
lanyards
you know until they went into target I
stayed out there nope sat in the car or
whatever they came out got in the van
and left but as they were getting back
in the van you know I read one of their
like lanyards and it said Billy Eilish
and so I instagrammed that and she had
not even 10,000 followers no I swear to
god no and so so I was like well I
listened to some of her music which
brought me back to SoundCloud to the
ocean eyes okay I had that song Joe and
so I listened to it and I was like that
is cool but she didn't have much out at
that point no and so well whatever no
and then she freaking blew up you know
and I was like nobody's gonna believe it
I saw her in the Kelso target bar you
want I believe you but I did know I
really did and no no I so wish I know I
don't know it's just super cool and I
just think that she
the bomb she was so cool no way wise
beyond her years but she's got a lot of
talent a lot of talent she does - she
Phineas brother have you so I've been
listening to the last couple days didn't
listen to you I lost a friend by Phineas
oh my god it's so good it's a it's it's
essentially just like a stripped yes him
singing with piano but he has like an
artistic video behind it I lost a friend
Phineas listener please let's do it fi
and n EAS other music video is just a
beautiful piece of art but that's so
crazy
I did not know that off to watch that
Allen video cuz I absolutely love
Maryland she's my favorite I just I just
wish she was my best friend so bad but
had no idea that Billy Eilish had takes
I had it yeah back and watch a lot of
her music videos cuz I was you know I
was interested and I was really
intrigued she that she I think from what
I understand pays her videographers know
to edit those scenes know where she no
you know no leaks out or whatever no
because she she she didn't want to be
you know that girl you know the new the
newest thing that I had to write like
she didn't want to be known for that
like she was Billy Eilish she's known
for her music not know you know and I
really admired that about her because
know like I got like I get it I get it
no but at the same time she asked her
and makes her that much cooler right I
mean in my eyes obviously but like and
so ya know in somebody else's eyes it's
like no like you know that doesn't stop
her from doing from singing from
whatever it's just a thing like it is
like like some people are back some
thing to some people but I guess I can
do I we I'm speaking for people with
vocal tics no well we can do anything
you can do you know and we might even be
able to do it better if the only thing I
that I don't do is I don't go to movies
I just don't know myself and that's why
I do go to
no and I've got into it with one person
at the movies but they moved and I
stayed in my original seat and all was
good so no but I don't know I typically
just don't put myself in that situation
right so if I need know like if I'm in a
spot where I need to be quiet I can know
but then after that I just you know does
it does it like like if you how does it
incorrect me if I'm using wrong
terminologies to I don't want to sound
arrogant like a flare up but probably
not the right does it ever get like more
intense so if I eat bad know if I am
nervous
right I know or like under no and you
know in like an uncomfortable
environment which this is it no maybe
discuss I'm on the spot of course no I
mean not even right now but like wind up
when I am or what if I don't sleep good
or no you know anything that would make
the average body flare up or feel
differently or not I don't know not
perform in a hundred percent is the same
thing but my just takes get more often
or no they're just more vocalized or
whatever mm-hmm but the only time I
don't do it is when I'm really
concentrated no or no or when I'm
sleeping I don't do it when I'm sleeping
no and weird I don't know why brain is a
magical thing
IIIi want I feel like I want to learn
more I feel like it's sticking out to me
and you said you said ADHD and OCD I
didn't know these were related my my OCD
has developed more so in my adulthood
like over the last few years really ya
know like bad no like no like knock I'm
not controlling but no like I know I do
I yeah I do have OCD right no like if I
have a weird shirt on underneath my
jacket I'll like sit you're in like
can't stop thinking about me not feeling
like because I have a motion well I mean
I don't know how yeah it's I'm always
know I wasn't diagnosed by a doctor I
just had a different life I don't think
you need to be you know yeah you know
you know what I mean like and some
doctors won't diagnose a real thing
and I feel like self-diagnosis is
sometimes better than but anyway yeah
yeah I think I diagnose is I think for
me like it's like okay well I seem to do
these things differently than other
people cool that's that's that and then
now how do I work with it like I have
like for my ADHD that wall over there
with all the sticky notes and stuff is
me trying to to organize my my brain and
all these things and so I also do like
honestly this podcast is like no it took
me so long to really get my first
episode going and just do it because I
was like dude I have ADHD I can't I
can't make someone sit here and I'm not
gonna be able to concentrate yeah yeah
but it's it's so far it's like no it
seems to be going well
and I am a lot easier on myself than I
thought I was gonna be like I don't have
had it much of it like it's like it's
just a conversation between two people
is a moment in time and there's a lot of
beneficial there do you it so it's
probably way long ago but um and you
don't have talking about if you don't
want to but a medication wise do you
remember back in the day do you take
like adderall or any of those sort of
things
no no no no they were so yeah something
along along the same ritalin is that the
same yeah it was same concept no on
something like that
no and fredo for a TD or 88 used to you
know but I was the opposite where like
no like I don't like no as a child I
could drink a cup of coffee and that
would have the reverse effect have you
heard of that like no no yes so those
you know know the medicines that were
supposed to like chill me out would hype
me up or vice versa
no so you know you know it was so much
going on in my brain at that time
developing anyway and then having you
know those big meds that are supposed to
cure you of whatever yeah nope and
playing with dosages and stuff like that
I don't I would just remember like you
know day to day thinking like I don't
want to feel like this sort of Franken -
yeah and you know like I was trying to
do like balance I got who I was in
middle school high school
and figure out like my medicine and my
homework and what I was gonna wear and
no you know whatever there's enough
going on when you're that age anyway but
um no I think yeah yeah I'm a big
advocate for like no no I don't like a
little like natural things that can help
you heal mm-hmm it's far as I don't like
if you want to smoke weed to chill out
find out if you want to go drink a rock
star and go on a run fine no you know
what and not saying that medicine is bad
if it if it works for you fine but I'm
just all about finding away do you no no
no to like balance who you are and feel
good about like except what you've got
like you said with your OCD like okay
you have it so how are you gonna deal
with it or how are you gonna know you
know am I gonna work it into my life not
to suppress it like like it's not very
I'm totally totally cool with people
just know like accepting who they are
what they have and no like no educating
others to what works for you might not
work for me but ya know somebody else it
he it worked for herself yeah I love
that conversation yeah I I think for me
I lot so if like for ADHD for me I
wasn't a couple of years I was on not
Ritalin but the adderall and now like
over the last it's probably been like I
don't know six seven minutes could be
totally off on that but I'm not on any
of that anymore
and I'm just like I found ways like
you're saying the more natural way it's
like honestly meditation yoga these sort
of things they make me feel so sane like
I you know sometimes I wake up and I'm
in a whirl I just I feel like I'm like I
can't focus I'm like obsessing over
things and I'm like I had some night or
whatever money nightmares dreams but but
I can have my routine where I you know
like all you know drink my water do my
stretches my meditation in it and it
helps me not shut those things up you
know those are you know these things are
a part of us but feel that feeling I'm
in control and they're not gonna stress
me yeah and no yeah we should find no
breathing techniques to have you have
you turned to breathing techniques oh
yeah oh yeah what do you like no no I
never do that no like the like the same
one
is not a specific well well specific one
that I like revert back to but like if
don't like I'm an anxious person I
always worry no I've always been a
warrior about things that haven't
happened things that might happen things
I think yeah you know if there's like I
will always worry no no but um I don't
know no like there's a nights where I
can't get to sleep
no I'll lay there and worry about like
some I said two years ago or what's
gonna happen at work tomorrow you know
yeah so though in the know just the
focus what was the link you shared of
the breathing do you but I think it was
I think that's the four seven eight yeah
yeah yeah we have to heal or something
that's a TED talk yeah yes it was a talk
but mine was like the five and five I
think
no like fire in do you knows blow out
five seconds for your mouth yeah that's
create a second change then like after
you start doing it no you're like oh my
gosh I was so focused on like counting
that number that I'm like like I feel
okay right now it's just like a matter
of like you know changing your mindset
or what your know the direction but I'm
totally into their breathing techniques
you know you know and I know you know I
know you and Jacy talked about it the
meditation I always feel like I'm doing
it wrong but is there a wrong way to do
it there's not a wrong way doing if
you're doing it yeah so you've never
tried it you have to try it but keep
trying it keep trying I think every day
biggest thing what I always for me in
meditation like that's of course like
the act of doing it like if you just do
it that's that's a good percentage but
so when you're sitting there okay ten
minutes I got to sit here I'm focus on
my breath yeah all that it takes is as
you're doing it and having I meditate
every day when daily meditator it still
happens to me every day I'm sitting here
and I'm focusing on my breath and I'm
focusing on whatever [__] weird whale
sounds I put on my computer or whatever
like sounds in the room and then you
know sure enough within a within a few
seconds within a minute some days I'm
thinking about like laundry and what I
need to do later later and all these
things but once you realize you're
thinking about those things and you're
like oh yeah you bring yourself back to
the breaths that right there that moment
right there is a bicep curl yes you
getting buff baby you get buff and it's
a it's training your
and it allows me to be more forgiving
with myself like sometimes because I'll
be obsessed we be like looping a thought
looping a thought and then once I
realized that I'm looping it instead of
for a while with my depression I would
realize that I've been limping or think
about some crazy stuff and then I would
get mad at myself like dude you just you
just wasted time like aha oh gosh but
now I don't have that I have that like
oh okay man you're just think about that
thing let's carrot let's get present
right now it's about you but you know
like in the beginning you know you think
like you don't people suggest that and
you're like don't okay you know Captain
Obvious like that doesn't work for
everybody no but I think it can you know
if you really give effort I really think
you can it's hard to see that it can
when you're like at your very dark
moment yeah yeah yeah but but a lot of
times the breath work can pull you out
of that dark moment to get you to like
okay well I'm not just looping that same
exact thought yeah now let's yeah Tony
Robbins always says change your state
before you try to you know a lot of
times we we have problems that come up
we have things that come up and we just
try to put them in the we try to stand
in the boxing ring we try to fight those
problems while we're stressed out but a
lot of times the best thing you could do
is say I'm not in the best state to
handle this right now so let's just work
on getting in a nice state and then I'll
have reassessment this this conversation
floating around we're getting a little
bit up here in time
was there anything that you wanted to
make sure the listeners knew of the
chunk Aaron loved podcast Matty be you
you be you I like that educate you got
something share know share it you know
there's something that needs to know no
don't don't talk to respond listen learn
yeah beautiful be you can't like I'm
gonna make you write be you on the wall
cuz I don't know if there's be you
anywhere on that wall know me make it
sure idea tune like that live on and be
yourself
oh yeah it's a Macklemore quote I love
Matty my shoulder I can [__] wasn't
necessarily because Macklemore but he
sung it sung it so he's suck he's on
dick I'm just
he said it so I like that I still like
it it's good good quote to live by yeah
I like Macklemore I think finding quotes
you know I'm big on quotes and I know
that an Instagram makes quotes kind of
like manat they could just see him all
the time but I've truly believed that
you give things power like you like you
if if a quote means something truly to
you you can just you could take it and
put it in your heart and carried around
and it can be powerful you know so
Maddie I really appreciate you I really
appreciate the conversation it was cool
to like meet someone who creates and
sees the world through beautiful lenses
I I just I love like the fact that you
said I don't see anybody has a stranger
like what's a stranger it's just like
this perfect thing I'm like oh man
that's so cool I feel honored that you
would come and explain explain your life
to me and chat it out and I'm grateful
that you listen to the podcast too
I think that's that's always cool to me
like I don't want I don't want to be
like one of those it's like yeah always
the first to like or comment or share
yeah yeah the next no but like literally
as soon as I'm done with a podcast I'm
like alright next oh yeah like I'm
always ready no you can't dish him out
fast know that but I feel like there's
so much info if my if no one relates to
mine don't really do another episode I
hope so like there's no is something you
know from each oh yeah each episode that
I can take a note from it's so cool and
I don't know some of these people and
some of them I thought I knew but really
got to know from their episode and it's
just taking that forward and I like it
thank you for sharing your you're crazy
brain and your crazy ideas that know a
lot of us can really relate to Wow well
thank you for listening Maddie all right
listeners have a good rest of you of
your day please drink some water and
please just be you have a good one
listen my bros we're quarantined right
now fear is a little high there's places
in our body that are little tense we've
been sitting more than usual we've been
thinking about weird stuff more than
usual don't forget to stretch don't
forget to drink water don't forget to go
easy on yourself
relax your shoulders right at this
moment right now
and just look around you're safe
everything's fine at this moment you're
going to handle what comes next with
ease with valor with courage with
bravery though there's uncertainty
there's also there's also love and fake
in hope and in community so just
remember your surroundings relax do what
you need to do don't forget to stretch
water all that take care of yourselves
pay attention to how much content you're
consuming we are inside there's a lot to
do there's a lot to consume on the
internet you could listen to all my
podcasts all day you can to somebody
else podcasts all day but sometimes you
got to take a break go outside and get
some fresh air stay six feet away from
people but get some fresh air live your
life take care of yourself
you